# Zemin Jin

E-mail: jinzm1982@gmail.com MSN: Iowrain@outlook.com

Phone: (86) 13401019493 jinzemin Skype:

Web Site: www.lowrain.com Github: www.github.com/lowrain

Marital Status: Gender: Male Married Date of Birth: 03/1982 Experience: 9 Years

Tongzhou District of Beijing Census register: Zhangjiakou City, Hebei Address:

## **Profile**

Proficient at C#, .NET Framework, ASP.NET, MVC, Sharepoint, SQL, Python, Javascript/jQuery, HTML, CSS, good at Web development. Have about 9 year's experiences in software development and really love this job. With strong learning ability, have great power on analyzing and resolving problems, enjoy on challenging to new technology and new field.

## Skills

• Language: C#, VB, SQL, Javascript, CSS, HTML5, Python

- · Web Server Framework: ASP.NET, MVC, Sharepoint, Flask
- Web Front-end Framework: jQuery, Bootstrap, Telerik, EXT JS
- · Database: SQL Server, MySql, SqlLite
- IDE: Visual Studio, PyCharm, XCode, Dreamweaver, Sharepoint Designer
- · Version Control: TFS, VSS, Github
- OS: Windows, Mac OS X, Linux(learning)

## Timeline

Tata Consultant Service Inc. 12/2013 - Now 07/2007 - 07/2013

Shinetech Inc.

09/2005 - 06/2007 Worked in advertising, training and software companies as ASP/ASP.NET developer

# Experience

WASABI (Microsoft internal project) Team Leader, Software Engineer/Tata Consultant Service Inc. && Microsoft 12/2013 ~ Now Lead two developers of TCS side, work in Microsoft Beijing west building with custom team. Develop new features, implement optimizing and refactoring, fix bugs.

Wasabi is a metadata management and data consumption application that provides common storage and metadata about the data used in multiple internal and external Online Services Division (OSD) and allows users to explore and consume this metadata.

C# 4.5 + ASP.NET MVC 4 (MVVM pattern) + jQuery + Knockout + Bootstrap + SQLServer 2012 + SD/TFS

#### Gaitar tab web site www.guitar123.net Personal Site

07/2013 ~ ?

Based on Python and Flask web framework, usage SQLAIchemy orm framework, responsive design usage bootstrap3+jQuery.

Source Code: www.github.com/lowrain/guitarfan Domain: www.guitar123.net

Python + Pycharm + Flask + WTForms + SQLAlchemy + MVC + Bootstrap + jQuery + SQLite/MySql + Github

Octant Business Management Suit Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

11/2007 - 08/2010 & 10/2011 - 07/2013

Octant was born out of the need to help organizations respond quickly and intelligently to proposal and contract requests. This product is based on Microsoft Sharepoint, contains 8 - 10 developer and tester. I participate throughout whole development processing and entire product from requirements analysis, design and implementation of functional module, WebPart/custom controls, page layouts, data access, iterative optimizing and defect repair.

Sharepoint2007/2010 + C# + Telerik Ajax controls + Javascript/jQuery + SQL Server 2008 + TFS/VSS

Janison E-learning Software Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

02/2011 - 07/2011

Janison is an Australian corporation, supports customers through the creation and development of client-centered, innovative, quality e-learning solutions. Include two sub projects, require high skill and quality.

Deloitte Academy System: Leaded another developer and worked at system maintainance, functionality expanding, new version development.

```
ASP.NET + VB + SQL Server + Web Service + jQuery + ComponentArt AJAX controls
```

Player by Rule & JService: Cooperated with Janison worked for updating Janison's core library "JService". It's data operation layout using EntityFramwork + Autfac. As while, created WCF service part for "Player by Rule" project. That is a MVC 3.0 application and based on JService. There were much business logic, technology analysis and communication between me and Janison team for achieving more powerful product.

```
ASP.NET + C# + SQL Server + WCF + EntityFramework + UnitTest + Ioc by Autofac + jQuery + Telerik
```

Finance Pad CRM System Team Leader, Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

09/2010 - 01/2011

Leaded four members' team to develop a web system of managing bank data and client/machine(Windows CE7 tablet). Base on ASP.NET MVC 2.0, UI usages EXT JS + AJAX, persistent layout and domain model integrate Nhibernate + Sql Server + WCF, add needed unit test for quality.

```
ASP.NET + C# + MVC + SQL Server + WCF + NHibernate + AJAX + EXTJS + Ioc by .Net Unity
```

Health Technology Research Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

04/2010 - 07/2010

This project includes four parts: a WCF message delivery system, a ASP.NET web site, a sharepoint portal and a MS CRM server. The web site integrates with Sharepoint and CRM is the data center. Message delivery system is a SOA project, it encrypt/decrypt, sign/verify and transfer between multi machines. The whole project of HTR shows users the services and products, provides content data search and manages customer relationship.

Established HTR web site and Sharepoint portal; Integrated HTR web site with Sharepoint portal user management system and CRM data; Researched and implemented WCF message delivery system with another developer according to client's requirement.

```
ASP.NET + Sharepoint + CRM + SQL Server + WCF
```

ECatalog Products Management Suit Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

08/2007 - 11/2007

This project was to build a products management suit for customs searching and seeing products in every category efficiently. There were many complicated business logic and data operations. Developed with responsibility for structure design, web page design, ASP.Net and database development.

```
ASP.NET + SQL Server + Javascript + HTML + CSS
```

EarthTone Software Engineer/Shinetech Inc.

07/2007 - 08/2007

Built web page templates with DIV layout and CSS. Insure templates pages must be up to Web 2.0 validation strictly and easy to integrate into ASP.NET system.

```
Dreamweaver + Fireworks + ASP.NET + HTML + CSS
```

Web site development, system maintenance Software Engineer

09/2005 - 06/2007

Worked at web development or company internal system maintenance in several corporations after graduated.

```
ASP.NET + ASP + PHP + SQL Server + My SQL + Javascript + HTML + CSS
```

### Education

#### Hebei Polytechnic University

9/2001 - 6/2005

Received a Bachelor degree of the Environmental Engineering

# **English**

CET4, be proficient in reading and writing in English.

#### Interests

Music, Photo, Riding, Coding, Comic, Movie, New Technique